杰思敏
Jasmine?
杰思敏 我们要迟到了 快点
Jasmine! We gonna be late, come on.
走吧
Let's go.
为什么他们穿着这些衣服 我们却没有
Why do they have on these suits and we don't?
我们眼前发生了这么多事情
Something's going on right in our face.
你们却沉迷在iPhone中
You're so stuck on those iPhones,
或者J phone 12之类的手机里
J phone 12s or whatever,
都爆炸吧
blow up in your hand.
你们百度不到发生了什么
You can't Google what's going on right now.
你们关心吗
Are y'all paying attention?
我们都没穿这些衣服 他们又何须穿
Why do they have on these suits if we don't?
为什么
Why?
他们到这来清理水源啦
They here to clean this water?
这水比魔鬼的嘴巴都脏
When this water been dirtier than the Devil's mouth
已有50年了
for 50 years.
现在他们想要清理啦
And now they want to clean it?
他们都计划好了 兄弟
They got plans for us, man.
似乎是乔治•杰特森（美漫《飞出个未来》里的角色）拒绝了
Looking like George Jetson rejects.
因为他们都虚弱
'Cause they weak!
虚弱的心
Weak hearts!
虚弱的肺
Weak lungs!
没有了面罩不能呼吸
Can't even breathe up here without a mask.
但是我们在地狱里被锤炼过了
But we was put through Hell to be purified.
各位兄弟姐妹 你们知道我的意思
You know what I'm sayin', brothers and sisters?
哥们 在监狱里他们对黑鬼可是很疯狂的
Man, it's crazy what jail will do to a nigga.
他们不在乎什么水 兄弟
They don't care about they water, man,
一定是有什么事发生了
there's something going on,
我们会查清楚的
we gonna get to the bottom of it.
幸好我现在是个传教士
And they lucky I'm a man of God right now.
你觉得他会为这个每天早晨排练吗
You think he rehearses this every morning?
否则他们早就把这双手拷走了
Or they would catch these hands.
看起来更像是即兴的
Seems a bit more impromptu.
已经2019年了
2019 out here!
他们还没出生时
We been yellin' about this water
我们就在为这水的事情呼喊了
since before they were born.
他们还没出生就开始了
Before they were born!
这趟公交车哪去了 我们去不了了
Where's this bus, man? We're not gonna make it.
你们会把我们独留在地狱
Y'all leave us the hell alone.
除非你们给予援手
Unless y'all really here to help us.
我们终将胜利
We'll get there.
他们在背后都谋划好了 兄弟
They got plans for us, man.
我们去不了了
We're not gonna make it, bro.
不是为你和我
Not for you and me.
请大家一定要
So I urge you!
为你们的土地抗争
Fight for your land!
为你们的家庭抗争
Fight for your home!
- 为你们... - 我们踩着滑板去吧
- Fight for your... - Let's skate.
知道这里是哪吗
This here?
这里是边境 兄弟
This is the edge, bro!
上帝临幸的最后一片土地
The final frontier of Manifest Destiny.
城市的边缘
Last edge of the city.
哥们 多走两步
Man, two steps further,
你们就能喝到那肮脏的盐水
you'll be drinking that filthy saltwater.
但是我们建造了这些轮船
But we built these ships.
挖掘的这些河道
Dredged these canals.
洛杉矶的人们从来都不知道这些
In the San Francisco they never knew existed.
然而现在他们想来开发了
And now they come to build something new?
所有的街区一半是过去的样子 一半却是未来的模样
Whole blocks half in the past, half in the future.
你们应该去洛杉矶闯一闯
But should you venture into their San Francisco,
他们掠夺的黄金都在那里
the one they pillaged for gold!
在那虚伪的城市里
Remember your truth!
不要忘记真理所在
In the city of facades.
带我一起去吧
Take me with you!
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
带我一起去 哥们
Take me with you, man!
别走 我们要去哪
Come on, where are we going?
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
等一下 我来了 我来了
Come on, I'm coming! I'm coming!
看看他们 看看你们
Look at them look at you.
真瞧不起你们
Look down at you.
我们建造了所有的东西
But we built them!
我们与这些房子同在
We are these homes!
它们注视着
Their eyes...
那伸出的房檐
Their pointed brims...
我们形影不离
We move if they move.
木料被我们的汗水浸透
Our sweat soaked in the wood.
镌刻着我们的身影
Gilded in our image.
这是我们的家
This is our home!
我们的家
Our home!
Our home.
谢谢大家
Thanks.
你确定他们走了吗
Are you sure they're gone?
吉姆
Jim?
我的意思是他们的车子不在
I mean, their car is gone.
我们到后面去看看
Let's check the back, man.
早上好
Good morning.
你好
How are you?
还记得那次他们在厨房吗
Remember that time they were in the kitchen?
吉姆
Jim!
还记得吗
Remember the kitchen?
当然
Yeah, sure.
但是 布鲁
But, bruh...
难道我没有跟你提过
Didn't I tell you
这些栅栏不是黑色的 上面长满了长春花
these railings are periwinkle, not black.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
我知道
Yeah, I got it.
我们不能再每两周就来一次了
We gotta start coming more than every two weeks, bro.
这个该死的花园就像场噩梦
This fuckin' garden's a nightmare.
下次我把爷爷的工具带上
I'll bring my grandpa's tools next time.
一定要带上
Please do.
墙纸正在剥落
Wallpaper's chipping.
这些人正在埋葬这所房子
These people are killing this house.
你又进不去
You're not goin' in though.
吉姆
Jim?
我是说
I mean...
不行
No?
他们肯定走了
They're definitely gone, though.
这次最好快点
Better be quick this time. Hmm?
我知道
Yeah, I know.
需要些时间
Takes time.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我随时就位
I'll be at my spot.
好的
All right.
快点
Quick.
好的
Okay.
- 老天 - 亲爱的
- Jesus, man! - Honey.
快滚开
Just get the heck out of here, man.
- 什么鬼 - 他也没伤害谁 玛尔
- What the fuck? - He's not hurting anyone, Mar.
哦 那他可以给我们的房子涂漆啦
Oh, he's painting the house now?
呃 嗯
Well, yeah.
别再修我的房子了
Stop fixing my house!
就快完成了 稍等
I'm almost done, just hold on.
为什么你不去给附近的房子上漆呢
Why don't you just paint the neighbors' houses?
他们的更糟糕
Theirs are worse than ours.
再稍等一下
Just hold on one second.
我的意思是 从某个方面来说
I mean, we appreciate it,
我们很感谢 但是
in some way, but, yeah...
着很奇怪
It's weird, man!
我就快完成了
I'm almost done.
听着 我们要报警了
Look, we will call the cops, man.
这次我真的要报警了
And I mean it this time.
不 我们不会报警
No, we're not gonna call the cops.
我们不会报警 别再来就行了
We're not calling the cops, just stop coming back.
我就快好了 请再稍等一下
I'm almost done, hold on, please, hold on.
呃 从我的鸟池边滚开
Ugh! Just get off my fucking birdie bath.
不 再
No, just...
滚出去
Get outta here, man.
- 那些花了我们3美元 - 好的
- Those were $3. - Fine.
下次我再弄完吧
I'll finish it next time.
- 上帝 - 还有下次
- God! - Next time?
哦 从...
Oh, just get...
从我的鸟池边滚开
Get the heck off my birdie bath!
记得给后面的绿植浇点水 或者让我来也行
Just water the plants in the back or I will.
哦
Oh!
哥们 你应该给我放风的
Bro! You were supposed to be the lookout!
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
真担心你
You were the one that was so worried.
我分心了
I got distracted.
哥们
Bro!
如果OG说的是对的呢
What if OG is right though?
你不能再吃外面的鱼了
You really gotta stop eating the fish out there.
我觉得还好啊
I think it's fine.
所有的鱼体内都有汞
All fish has mercury.
我晓得 我还见过带屌的海鸥呢
I know, but I saw a seagull with a dick, bro.
好吧 那一定是雄性的
Well, so I guess it's a male.
不 就像 就像人的屌一样
No, like, bro, like a human dick.
哦 恶心的风滚草 小娘们
Oh, nasty-ass tumbleweave. Pussy.
- 野啊 哥们 - 怎么了 黑鬼
- Wild, bro. - Wassup, nigga?
- 不敢动了是吗 - 给我擦鞋吧
- Ain't tryin' do nothin'. - Scuff my shoes up, huh?
我才不会做那些狗屎事情
I ain't tryin' do that bullshit...
在我把那坨屎甩在你脸上之前 赶紧给我停手
Stop playin' before I slap the shit out your face.
把你的屁眼闭上吧 黑鬼
Man, shut your ass up, nigga.
好了 我才不会去追你的
All right, I ain't finna chase you,
我不玩了
you play too much, bro.
我没有在这里把你干翻 你该感到幸运
You lucky I don't beat your ass out here, bro.
科菲
Kofi!
- 最近怎么样啊 兄弟 - 大家好啊
- What's good, brother? - What's up with y'all?
嘿 我昨天去Moms知道吗
Hey, you know I seen Moms last night, right?
她就像是在顶点
She was looking like she was
有点迷了
missing a little bit on the top.
我是说我们用一样的水洗澡 吉姆
I mean we shower in the same water, Jim.
现在黑鬼们都要一起洗澡了吗
So niggas takin' showers together now?
可能已经洗过了
Probably was.
那可太古怪了
That's fruity.
我在跟他讲不要吃鱼
I was trying to tell him not to eat the fish,
因为水有毒
because the water is toxic.
呃 当然了
Well, duh.
因为他们在哪里造了个
That's 'cause they built the atomic bomb
原子弹啊
right there, nigga.
那不是真的
I don't think that's true.
他说什么
What'd he say?
- 该死 - 头回见 这倒是真的
- Damn. - First thing, that's true.
哥们 那双鞋也不是真的
Bro, them shoes ain't true,
你那漂亮的屁股
I know your Jesus-lookin' ass
没有说话吧
ain't talkin', bro.
- 假的 - 绝对是假的
- Them things is phony. - They're definitely phony.
到底是怎么回事呢 哥们
What about cuz, man?
你昨晚应该给我打电话的
You was supposed to call me last night.
- 怎么回事... - 这哥们是个猫科动物
- What happened with... - Oh, yeah, dude is a cat.
看他的头发 他可能是只猎豹
You see his hair, he might be a cheetah.
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
我想见管事的
I'd like to see the man in charge.
这里
In here.
他正在带他去长官的房间
He's walking him into the Chief's office.
天啊
Oh, dear.
我要报告一场谋杀
I want to report a murder.
- 坐 - 这又是谁
- Sit down. - Now, who's that?
埃德加-奥莱恩
Edgar O'Ryan.
在哪里发生的
Where was this murder committed?
- 艾德蒙 奥布莱恩 - 洛杉矶
- Edmund O'Brien. - San Francisco.
哦哦哦 是他
Oh. Oh, him, yeah, yeah.
谁被谋杀了
Who was murdered?
我
I was.
什么
What?
- 怎么回事 - 你继续看就知道了
- How? - Just watch it.
我没时间陪你玩
I don't have very much time.
孩子 给我递瓶啤酒
Hey, hand me my beer, son.
- 是的 - 好
- Yes, sir. - Yeah.
好
Yeah, okay.
奥布莱恩在抽烟
O'Brien is smoking a cigarette
- 在他的办公室里 - 好的
- in his office. - Okay, yeah.
- 秘书在歇息 - 她漂亮吗
- Secretary's perched. - She pretty?
嗯...
Mmm...
- 漂亮吗 - 她  她漂亮
- Yeah? - I'd say... I'd say she is.
你个色狗
You dog.
嘿 蒙哥
Hey, Mont!
- 蒙哥马利 - 嗯
- Montgomery! - Mmm?
我怎么才能把那俩货
How do I get their old croissant-throwing asses
赶出房子
out of the house?
我尿在他们的桌子上怎么样
What if I peed on their table?
这样 我爬上那个鸟池
Like, what if I climbed up the birdie bath,
闯进去
broke in and just peed
然后尿在那个傻逼小黄桌上
all over that stupid little yellow table?
那会毁了地板吧
Wouldn't that ruin the floors?
有道理
Yeah, I guess you got a point there.
哦
Oh.
他们会不会让我住那
You think they'd let me live there as, like,
当个看房人之类的
a caretaker for the house?
不
No.
那完蛋了
That's fucked up.
我照顾房子可挺有一手的
I mean, I take pretty good care of the house,
至少我自己是这么认为的
I think so at least.
你是挺有一手的
Yeah, you do.
你待在这也挺好的 吉姆
We like having you here, Jim.
我知道
I know, bro.
但是
But...
不管在哪都不像在家一样
You know there's no place like home.
嗯
Yeah.
晚安 桃乐茜
Goodnight, Dorothy.
♪♪ 在家庭聚会上
♪♪ At the family reunion
♪♪ 我们向你们介绍
♪♪ Who we introducing
♪♪ 一位表哥阿罗
♪♪ I got a cousin Arrow
♪♪ 在一场宴会上
♪♪ He used to have a feast
♪♪ 他与他的狐朋狗友一起
♪♪ He was with the shit
♪♪ 现在这黑鬼是个牧师
♪♪ Now that nigga is a priest
♪♪ 在家庭聚会上 ♪♪
♪♪ At the family reunion ♪♪
为什么他们穿了制服 我们没有
Why they got suits on and we don't?
先生
Sir?
我们是来保护你的
We're here for your protection.
是来帮助你的
We're here to help you.
你们来这帮助我吗
You here to help me?
Me? This water been filthier
臭气熏天几十年了
than the Devil's mouth for years!
先生
Sir.
这是个小家伙
Yeah.
就是这个了
All right?
这是个小家伙
Small guy.
就是这个了
He's perfect.
嘿 今天早晨写东西了吗
Hey, you get any writing done this morning?
嗯...
Um...
写作就是不断修改
Writing is rewriting.
这都是过程中的一部分
It's all part of the process.
好吧 你说得对
Yeah, you got it, though.
嗯...当然了
Hmm... Yeah, man.
怎么回...
What the f...
你们住这都十二年了
Y'all been here 12 years,
还是照顾不好这所房子
still can't take care of this house.
嘿 保罗
Hey, Paul.
嘿
Hey!
我扶着你呢
I got you.
- 嗨 - 吃你的香蕉去吧
- Hi. - Eat your banana.
- 去你的 - 嘿
- Fuck you. - Hey.
你是个好人
You're a nice man.
你是个好女人
You're a nice woman.
我又不认识你
But I don't know you.
嗯
Well, yeah.
事实上你挺了解我的
You know me pretty well, actually.
你也不是我丈夫
But you aren't my husband.
你有点太年轻了
You're a little too young for me.
我是年轻
I am young.
永远年轻
I'm always young.
你是个好男人
You're a nice man.
哦 谢谢
Oh, thank you.
你是个好女人
You're a nice woman.
你个小娘炮
You old marshmallow, cream puff ass,
大大的屁股 圆圆的脸蛋
candied yam-ass nigga, cream puff-ass nigga.
闭上你的臭嘴
Shut up, bitch, bro.
- 你闭上吧 - 拉住他
- You bitch. - Hold this shit.
我要把你干到
I should snatch your one-ass dread,
lookin' like a fuckin' Rastafarian sperm.
你们把我坑了
You got me fucked up.
- 我们把你坑了 - 怎么了
- We got you fucked up! - We did!
你就会说些这吗
That's all you gotta say?
该怎么办?逃跑吗?
Man, what I'm supposed to do, take off?
I don't care about none of that shit.
我知道 我只是不知道该说什么
I know, I just ain't got nothin' else to say.
说白了
Man, I put that on a fact,
这黑鬼就是个贱货
that this nigga's a bitch, man.
- 是不是?- 干他娘的
- Is that sure, man. - Man, fuck this nigga.
你好哇 黑鬼
'Sup, nigga?
How are you, nigga?
你好哇 黑鬼
I hope she's not home.
那个花园
That garden...
有太多事要做了
We have so much to do.
要锄地
We have to rake it.
要播种
We have to weed it.
- 要...- 吉姆
- We have to... - Jim.
那是不是你以前住过的车?
Isn't that the car you used to live in?
天哪
Oh, God.
吉米
Jimmie!
你好啊 臭货
What up, filth-smellin' motherfucker?
要打个便车吗?
Do you need a ride?
吉米
Jimmie!
怎么了
What's happenin', baby?
显老的货赶紧滚上车
Get your young, old-looking ass in the car.
摆臭脸
Daddy face.
吉米
Jimmie!
天哪 公交车哪去了
Oh, my God, where is this bus?
要是你再不把你那穿着好时衬衫的老父亲带上车的话
Man, if you don't get your up the father from Good Times shirt-wearing ass
我就...
in this car...
你真的要带把铲子上公交吗
You really gonna ride in the bus with a shovel?
土包子快上车
Get your farming ass in this car.
吉米小婊砸
Jimmie the farmer with your bitch ass.
来 笑一个
Come on, laugh a little bit, Jimmie, shit.
车还是老样子
Still the same.
Yep, I like what you and your dad did with it.
以至于带着开出来?
So much you drove off with it?
不 我借的 我没有 别这样
No, I borrowed it, I didn't, just, come on...
开出来 借的
I drove off with it... I borrowed it, shit.
跟你说 有天我看到你爸了
Matter of fact, I seen your dad the other day.
他挺好 有点寂寞
He was good and lonely.
By hisself.
好的
Okay.
我跟他说你得养只狗或猫
I told him you need to get you a cat or a dog,
或者女人啥的也行
or woman or something, nigga, damn.
他独守空房
He's home alone...
嗯 没在房子里 但还是一个人
Well, he ain't at home, but he's alone.
一个人流浪
He's alone with no home.
你不也一个人住在车里
Well, you live in a car by yourself.
是 但是我不寂寞
Yeah, but I... But I'm not alone.
人们都喜欢我
People like me.
我受欢迎
I'm liked.
孤独的黑鬼
Lonely ass nigga.
你上次和你爸一起是什么时候
When the last time you hung out with your daddy?
几周前吧 不确定
Couple weeks ago, I dunno.
几周前?那黑鬼现在很需要你
Couple weeks ago? The nigga needs you today.
见鬼
Shit.
人们生孩子就是
That's what... That's what people have kids for,
想要个伴
so they can have some companionship!
Somebody to hang out with.
所以我才没要孩子
That's why I ain't had no kids.
我乐得清静
'Cause I don't wanna be bothered.
你爸不想要这辆车
Your daddy don't want this fuckin' car, man.
- 嘿 - 嗯?
- Hey. - Hmm?
那是不是萨沃伊别墅?
Wasn't that the Savoy House?
以前是
Oh, sure was.
有100个混蛋在那里住过 还有租金管控
It was 100 motherfuckers in there, rent-controlled.
他们以为自己拥有了这所房子
They thought they owned that shit.
领主把他们都烧死了
The landlord burned all of the people outta there.
因为 吉米
'Cause see, Jimmie,
你从来不会拥有什么
you never really own shit.
这车不是我的
This car ain't mine.
But it never was yours.
你决不会拥有它
You never own shit!
什么鬼
What the fuck?
嘿 发生什么了
Hey, what's goin' on, man?
忙着呢 兄弟
No se, bro.
呃 先生
Uh, sir...
发...发生什么了
What's... What's going on?
哦 天哪
Oh, God.
她在搬家
She's moving.
和她姐姐争得像个疯子一样
Fighting like crazy with her sister.
家里有人死了的时候
When someone dies in the family,
白人都要这么做
that's what white people do.
这是她的 这是他的 这是我的
This is for her, this is for him, this is mine.
房子是谁的?
Who's gonna have the house?
这房子不再是他们的了?
So they lost the house?
房子会归谁?
Who's gonna possess the house?
他们就争啊 争啊 争啊
They're just fighting, and fighting, and fighting.
What's gonna happen to it now?
为什么她妈妈死了他们就得搬出来
Why'd they have to move out 'cause her mom died?
不知道
I don't know.
他们没有什么品位
They were tasteless,
但至少不会糟蹋房子
but at least they didn't fuck it up.
亲爱的 10美元
Well, that will be $10, hun.
从什么时候开始10美元的
Since when?
从你吃上最好的60特趣开始
Since that's the best deal you're gonna get on 60 Twix.
我没说60 阿姨 我说的是16
I didn't say 60 Twix, Auntie. I said 16.
我怎么会吃60的
How I'm gonna eat 60 Twix?
我又不了解你
I don't know your life.
搞得跟好事多超市一样
You act like you in Costco or something like that.
你这里又不是好事多
You ain't Costco.
嘿 你要是想去好事多 就去啊
Hey, you can go to Costco if you need to.
- 你是乐仕高 - 快走吧
- You Rosco. - Go right now.
你第一次检查的时候 我就是16
Sixteen, first time you had a check, when I was 16.
吉姆 吉姆
Jim. Jim.
吉姆
Jim.
吉姆?
Jim?
先生
So, gentlemen.
有什么可以为您效劳的
What can I do for you?
我们对一所房子挺感兴趣的
Yeah, we're curious about a house
在金门费尔摩附近
on Golden Gate near Fillmore.
- 好的 - 959号
- Mmm-hmm. - It's 959.
灰色 有金色镶边的
It's the gray, it's got the gold trim.
- 呃...-是 是
- Uh... - Yup, yup.
是 有那个...
Yup, with the, um...
那个巫师帽
The witch hat.
对对
Yeah, exactly.
耶
Yeah!
我很清楚你说的
I know exactly what you're talking about,
- 那个地方很特殊 - 嗯
- that place is very special. - Hmm.
我在去学校的路上
I used to drive past that house
开车经过那里
on the way to school every day.
哪个学校?
What school did you go to?
圣伊格纳斯
I went to St. Ignatius.
你也是那的吗
You from here, too?
嗯 第三代 事实上我去过里尔登
Yeah, third generation, I went to Reardon, actually.
- 真的吗 - 嗯
- Really? - Yeah,
我们过去在哪里和你们一起踢足球
we used to play y'all in football all the time.
去你们的 你们那么强
Fuck you, you used to kill us in football.
是 是啊
Yeah, yeah.
我本来不太想说的 但是...
I didn't wanna say that, but...
太棒了 美好的回忆
That's awesome, right on.
是待售吗?我还没收到消息
But, so, it's for sale? I didn't hear about that.
我不确定
Well, I'm not sure.
好像是那里的住户和她姐姐
It seems like the owner and her sister
在争房子
are fighting over it.
她妈妈好像去世了
But I guess her mom died.
噢
Ah, man.
听起来像是房产事宜
I don't know, that sounds like an estate thing.
有点尴尬
That's a sucky situation.
我的意思是
But, I mean...
为了那样的一座房子
With a house like that,
她们可能争得数年不休
they could be fighting over that for years.
而房子却独自没落
While it just sits there.
有点可惜
It's a pity.
房子...真的空无一物吗?
So it's really just... Just empty?
糟透了
It's fucked up, right?
非常糟糕
So fucked up, like I...
烦死人了 街上那么多人
Bothers me, there's all these people in the street
这些老旧的大房子
and these big old houses
却在吃灰
are just sitting there collecting dust.
话又说回来 又能怎样呢
But shit, what else can you say?
太不公平了
The fucking injustice of it!
是啊
Yeah.
蒙特 我们来了 宝贝
Mont! We here, baby!
他们以重建城市的名义
Spoiling all the fun,
夷平了这里
leveling most of this neighborhood
破坏了这些美好事物
in the name of Urban Renewal.
很抱歉你们没有了家和时髦的店铺
Sorry about your homes and your funky shops.
你们可以在停车场前面的
You can set up a shoeshine stand
喜互惠超市摆擦鞋摊
in front of the parking lot at Safeway.
然而你们这些真诚的人们
But you distinguished truth-seekers
却还知道 在一个叫 西部哈莱姆 的地方
want to know about the real hep cats who hung out here,
在一个叫 西部哈莱姆 的地方
in the "Harlem of the West,"
就想这座漂亮的房子一样
where a few of these homes did survive.
有些房子存活了下来
Like this beauty here,
建造于1800年左右
which was built clear back in the 1800s.
在黑人来之前
Before the black thing,
这都是日本人
this was all Japanese,
直到罗斯福的冲锋队把他们赶走
till FDR's stormtroopers rounded them up into camps.
这座房子建造于上个世纪四十年代
This house was built in the 1940s.
大家和我们的邻居打个招呼
Say hi to our neighbor here, everybody.
嗨
Hi.
事实上100年之后才会有这种风格
That would actually be about 100 years late for this style.
从那金色的镶边可以看出
We can see from his gingerbread trim,
是建造于19世纪50年代
this was built sometime in the 1850s.
呃 1946年
Uh, 1946!
那我就要和你争一争了 大兄弟
I'm gonna have to disagree with you there, dude man.
在那个时候没有建筑师会有这种风格
No architect in the 1940s was building in this style.
That's probably true, but this wasn't built by an architect.
是我的爷爷建造的
My grandfather built this.
他在二战的时候来到这里
He came here World War II,
圈了这块地 盖了这所房子
he bought this lot and he built this house.
楼梯
The stairs.
这些窗户
These windows.
柱子 拱门
The columns. The archways.
那个巫婆帽
The witch hat.
栏杆扶手
The balustrades.
那些亮亮的鳞瓦片
The fish scales.
阳台
This balcony.
还有那堵可以让你们滚出去的墙
That wall to keep y'all the fuck out.
全部
All of it.
都是吉米·菲尔斯 用他的双手建造的
By Jimmie Fails I, with his own two hands.
就在1946年
In 1946.
喔
Wow.
挺神奇的
That's pretty amazing.
嗯
Well...
我们去下一站吧
Let's move on to our next stop.
帕蒂·赫斯特曾任性不出的
The closet Patty Hearst
壁橱 在之前...
willfully hid herself in, before trotting on down...
怎么了?发生什么了?
What's good with that? What's going on?
感觉像英国的皇帝一样
Feel like the King of England.
吉米君王 挥手
King Jimmie. Wave.
跟将军挥手
Wave to the General.
- 嘿 将军 - 像画圈一样
- Hey, General. - Yeah, but it's like a circle,
用你的胳膊肘
with your... With your elbow.
然后像用杯子装空气一样
Yeah, and then cup the air.
像回事了
That's kind of the thing there.
- 哦 对 - 很好
- Oh, yeah. - Yeah, that's good.
这座房子很美 吉米
It's a beautiful house, Jimmie.
比我想象中的还美
More beautiful than I could have imagined.
是啊
Yeah.
还没到那个程度
It's not quite there yet.
太多狄更斯的了
I mean, enough Dickens.
查尔斯·狄更斯
Charles Dickens.
腓力斯人 哥们
Philistines, bro.
蒲鲁斯特
Proust!
普拉思
Plath!
休斯
Hughes!
吉米 朗斯顿·休斯
Jimmie! Langston Hughes!
他们把他留这了
They left him!
哥们
Bro!
腓力斯人
Philistines!
蒙特
Mont.
醒醒
Wake up.
我有个主意
Got a plan.
疯了
It's crazy.
我上次来这的时候 这些野草比我还高
Last time I was here, these weeds was taller than me.
她高兴见到我们吗?
She's expecting us?
是的长官
Yes, sir.
- 姑姑 - 吉米
- Auntie! - Jimmie!
太好了
Yes!
哦 见到你太高兴了
Oh! So good to see you!
- 你气色不错 - 谢谢
- You look good! - Thank you.
- 嘿 - 这是蒙特
- Hey! - This is Mont.
你们不热吗?你想...
Nice to meet you. Oh.
Y'all not hot? Like, you want...
- 热死了 - 把夹克脱了吧
- It's hot as hell out here. - Take your jacket off.
没人会偷的
Ain't nobody gonna steal your jacket.
这附近挺和谐的
This is a nice neighborhood.
他最好别把我滑板弄坏了
Man, he better not break my damn board.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你得谢谢他
You should be thanking him.
是他把那滑板拿出来的
He's the one that helped me pick out that board.
而且...
And besides...
有时候单是看着
Sometimes it's just
就挺好的
nice to watch.
嗯
Mmm.
瑞吉 表演一下那个招式
Ricky, do that trick you used to do, baby.
漂亮
Nice, baby.
你们都太可爱了
Y'all hella cute.
噢 谢谢
Aw, thank you.
那么
So,
你还有多少这些旧东西?
how much of this stuff do you still have?
真的假的?
Really?
你还有多少这些旧东西?
How much of this stuff do you have?
就这么直接?
You just, no segue or nothin'?
你就是来这看这些东西的?是吧?
You just came to see the stuff, huh?
姑姑
Auntie...
我有了一个住处了
I got my first place.
哇
Whoa.
真的吗?
Really?
在城里?
In the city?
是的
In the city.
看看你
Look at you!
你们一定都把自己照顾的挺好
Y'all must be doing pretty well to afford a spot there.
嗯 幸运而已
Yeah, we got lucky.
- 嗯 - 就是太空荡了
- Mmm-hmm. - It's super empty, though.
不是你爸把你送来的吧
Your daddy didn't send you here, right?
- 不是 - 真的吗？
- No. - You sure?
发誓
I swear to God.
我可不希望
'Cause I hope he's done
他老是管着你
dragging you into his schemes.
姑姑 只有我们
Auntie, this is for us.
好吧
Okay.
好的
我为你感到骄傲
I'm proud of you, Jayboe.
- 真的 - 谢谢
- Really am. - Thank you.
我想念那座城市了
I miss that city.
哦 哦
Oh! Ooh!
你还是很帅 宝贝
You still look good though, baby.
还是很帅
You still look good!
嗯
Mmm.
哦 天哪
Oh, my goodness.
嗯
Mmm.
天 你说的一些就是这些了吗?
Damn, I knew you had some of it, but is this everything?
你爸还没烧的都在这了
Everything your dad didn't smoke up.
抱歉 出来的时候有点急
Sorry, came out a little harsh.
没事
I'm fine.
这些真的都是你的吗
You really got all of this.
是
Yep!
数不胜数
Got as much as I could.
打开那个
Open that.
太棒了
That's amazing.
嗯 我知道
Yeah, I knew that,
比这个家里的任何人都清楚
out of everybody in this family,
你会回来找这些东西
you would be the one that come looking for this stuff.
那么...
So...
我能...
I can...
所有的吗?
Everything?
都是你的
It's yours.
- 谢谢你 - 当然啦
- Thank you. - Hell, yeah.
瑞吉 把车开来
Ricky, get the truck!
你俩还会回来吗?
You guys good back there?
再见
Bye.
谢谢
Thank you.
瑞吉没住进这个房子吗?
So, Ricky never lived in the house?
没有 旺达在我们迷路分开之前没见过他
No, Wanda didn't meet him until after we lost it.
- 你好 先生 - 嘿
- Hello, sir. - Hey!
我是吉米·菲尔斯 我们一直没有机会见面
I'm Jimmie Fails, we haven't had the chance to meet yet.
- 哦哦 是啊 - 是
- Oh. Oh, yeah. - Yeah.
欢迎来到这里
Welcome to the neighborhood.
是的是的 见到你很高兴
Yeah, oh, yes...
欢迎
Welcome.
蒂姆 蒂姆·埃勒瑞
Tim! Tim Ellory.
是的是的 见到你很高兴
Sure, sure, nice to meet you, man.
这个市场流通的很快啊
It's a fast-moving market,
我都不记得有牌子挂起来
I don't even remember a sign going up.
哦 不需要...
Oh, it didn't need to, but...
听着 蒂姆 我想告诉你
Look, Tim, I want you to know
我会成为你最好的邻居的
I'm going to be the best damn neighbor you ever had.
嗯...
Well...
- 好吧 吉米 谢谢 - 荣幸之至
- All right, Jimmie, thank you. - My pleasure.
呃 我得走了
Uh, well, you'll have to pardon me,
有好多事要做...
we've got lots to do, but...
- 当然 - 见到你很高兴
- Of course, oh, yeah. - Very nice to meet you, yeah.
刚才那是他妈怎么回事
What the fuck was that all about?
我想一边看报纸
I wanna drink my coffee
一遍喝咖啡挠屁股
and scratch my ass while I read the paper.
你不读报纸 吉米
You don't read the paper, Jimmie.
因为我一直没有一个家去读
'Cause I never had a home to read it in.
该死
Shit.
我们可以搞派对
We could throw parties.
你可以表演你的戏
You could put on one of your plays.
我们可以
We could yell.
- 邻居 吉米 - 邻居怎么了
- The neighbors, Jimmie. - Oh, the neighbors?
- 哼 - 我现在有邻居了
- Hmm. - I got neighbors now.
干得漂亮
Attaboy.
这黑鬼是个贱货
This nigga is a bitch.
我没事 别装了
I'm a soft nigga. Run the fake, nigga!
所有的事情
On everything, bro.
那小孩子就是个胆小鬼
Man, this kid was a straight sucker.
你撒谎
You lyin', bro,
所有的事情都是 胆小鬼
on everything, bro, straight sucker, bro.
我发誓 告诉他发生了什么
Tell him what happened. I swear to God.
昨晚一辆货车在这停了
Man, last night, a white van pulled up.
我发誓
I swear to God, bro.
科菲就像个胆小鬼一样逃跑了
This nigga Kofi ran like a straight bitch!
- 他没说谎 - 他会害死我们的
- He not lyin'! - He gonna get us killed!
你们说我跑了?我没跑
You niggas sayin' I ran? I didn't run, nigga!
别再说废话了
Man, fuck what you niggas talkin' about.
闭嘴吧 他就是个胆小鬼
Shut the fuck up, bro, he's a straight sucker, bro.
嘿 他让我们都掉价了
Hey, hey, man, he got us looking like bitches, bro.
要是让我碰上这事
If I've gotta get on this thing,
我要问死你
I'm gonna be questioning you!
你本来应该像表亲一样帮我
You supposed to be my cousin.
你本来也可以不跑
I'mma bet you supposed to not run, nigga,
那才是你应该做的
and that's what you supposed to do.
好了 好了 好了 好了 兄弟们
All right, all right, all right, all right, bro.
所有人闭嘴
All right, everybody shut up, bro.
科菲 发生什么了
Kofi, what happened, bro?
告诉他
Tell him.
呃...
Uh...
为什么
Why?
- 告诉他 - 你跑了吗?
- Tell him! - Did you run, nigga?
没有
Nah, I didn't run, nigga.
就跟你说吧
I told you!
- 撒谎 撒谎 - 去你的
- Lyin', lyin'. - Man, fuck you, nigga.
抓住他
Get on him!
哇啊哦
Wow.
- 打我 - 什么？
- Hit me, bro. - Man, what?
打我
Hit me, bro.
为什么 你是我兄弟
And for what, you supposed to be my folks.
嘿 科菲 打他
Hey, Kofi, hit that nigga, bro.
耶 就是这样
Yeah! Come on, bro!
快 快 抓住他
Yeah! Let's go! Let's go! Get on him!
打我 打我
Hit me, bro! Hit me, bro!
他就是个贱货
This nigga's a bitch!
打我啊 快来
Hit me, man! Come on!
伙计们 伙计们
Guys! Guys!
就是这样
Great, it's great.
很好 很好
Very good, very good.
停 很好很好
Cut! Very good, very good.
好 好 棒极了
Good, good, excellent.
嘿 好消息是
Good. Hey, great news
你们的工作完成的很好
is you're all doing marvelous work.
- 什么?- 祝贺你们
- What? - Congratulations,
不简单
it's not easy.
我相信你
I believe you.
但是我觉得还能更进一步
But I know it can be deeper.
- 你他妈在说什么? - 嘿
- Fuck you talkin' about? - Hey.
记得斯坦尼斯拉夫斯基
Remember Stanislavski.
你他妈在干什么
Fuck are you doin', man?
格罗托夫斯基或者斯拉夫斯基...
Grotowski or Slavski...
契科夫 布鲁
Chekhov, bruh.
- 这些都是伟人 - 我有点迷惑
- These are the greats. - I'm confused, bro.
你挺好的
You're okay there.
你不是导演 兄弟
怪胎 快滚
Bro, you're not a director, bro.
Man, take your weird ass outta here.
继续营造
Keep building it.
那货来这我不舒服
Nigga, I don't like when that nigga come around here, bro.
这货就是个贱货
Bro, this nigga's a bitch.
说啊 我抓住他了
Say the word, I get on this nigga, bro!
开始
Here we go.
帮我看下 马上回来
Watch this for me real quick, bro.
我知道
I know.
我有天看见你的表亲艾尔
I seen your cousin, Al, the other day.
他说"嘿 詹姆斯叔叔"
Aight, "Hey, Uncle James!"
我看着他说"我不认识你
I look like, "Man, I don't know you,
在那闲逛 像个弗里斯科水果杯
"down there struttin' around, like a Frisco fruit cup."
他爸都快气疯了
I know his daddy mad as hell.
你还在玩滑板吗
You still skateboarding?
没
Nah.
哼
Hmm.
怎么了
What?
来帮我把这些剪剪
Come here, help me cut these out.
确保这些颜料流得畅通
And make sure the color bleeds all the way through,
不要白边
no white edges, aight?
是的长官 老样子
Yes, sir. Same as always.
是啊
Yeah.
老样子
Same as always.
嘿 你还记得我们以前挤在一起的那个仓库吗?
Hey, you remember that, uh, warehouse we squatted at?
离开埃尔多拉多之后吗?
After we lived in the El Dorado?
我们因为没交税被赶出来
We lost that ' cause we didn't pay taxes, right?
嗯 没交
Hell, nah.
我交了我们的那一份
I paid our fair share of tax on that.
但是谁在乎呢 那个舒服的狗窝
But who cares, old drafty-ass roach nest.
不是睡在那
Shit, it was that,
就是露宿街头
or sleeping on the street with your little ass.
我很感激 爸
Well, I appreciate it, Dad.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
我现在有个地方住了
So, say I'm at a place now
住户离开了
and the owners left it,
我得交税
I'm gonna pay taxes on it...
你的电气费都是你的名义吗?
And you put gas and electric in your name?
是的 马上就要弄那个 我知道的
Right, I'm gonna do that next, you know I know.
好的 和你老爹一样
Okay, doin' it like your old man.
很好
That's good.
没人会去检查吧
And nobody's come to check on it?
没 那里很空荡
Nope. It's empty.
好
Good.
你要花点时间了
That buys you time.
他们已经走了三年了?
And they been gone three years?
不是 最近才走的
Nah, just recently.
等等 什么?
Wait, what?
他们还在那里的时候你就去整修房子了?
You were workin' on it while they were still in it?
是
Yeah.
在哪里
Where is this house?
菲尔莫
It's the house in Fillmore.
喔
Wow.
我们的老房子
Our old house.
什么意思 我们的老房子
What the fuck you mean, our old house?
你见过那房子吗?
Have you seen that house?
见过
Well, yeah, I mean,
我经常去那里
I be over there all the time.
那你应该知道那不是你的老房子
Then you know that's not your old house
那也不是黑人聚集区
and that's not your black-ass neighborhood.
混小子
Little disrespectful lyin' ass.
- 你什么意思 - 我知道你在玩滑板
- What are you talking about? - Nigga, I know you skateboard!
是
Yeah.
我看见那玩意儿了
Yeah, I see all that shit out there.
大家都玩
Everybody's little path.
我就在你们30步远的地方
I'm like 30 steps ahead of y'all.
继续
Go on.
拿着
Get!
不准在说房子的事了
You know we don't talk about that house no more.
放下赶紧滚
Put the shit down and go!
嘿 你等了很久吗
Hey, you been waiting here long?
很久
Hella long, bro.
我还是踩滑板走吧
I might just skate.
那挺好
Well, that"s nice.
傻逼二货
This guy fucks.
嘿 桑迪 桑迪 这有个傻逼二货
Hey, Sundeep. Sundeep, bro, this guy fucks.
傻逼二货
This guy fucks!
傻逼二货傻逼二货
This guy fucks! This guy fucks!
哦 这个城市真是
Oh, this city.
我深有体会 哥们
I already know, bro.
草
Fuck!
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
这都是什么?
What is all this?
喔
Wow.
我爸以前干活时
A little room I used to come in
我经常去的小房间
when my dad was doing his thing.
很棒吧
It's cool, right?
是啊
Yeah, man.
你今天见到他了吗？
Did you see him today?
怎么样？
How'd it go?
他说这主意糟透了
He said this was a bad idea.
你不是说他是个白痴吗
Thought you said he was an idiot.
不 他只是因为失去了房子而生气而已
Nah, he's just mad 'cause he lost the house.
但是要是我们不该来这呢？
But what if we shouldn't be here?
谁不该来这？
Who should be here more?
嗯？
Hmm?
百万富翁吗？
Some millionaire?
房子看起来很棒他们才想要
They'd want it 'cause it looks nice.
但这都是你的努力换来的
You're the reason it looks nice, Jim.
我不知道
I don't know.
什么鬼
What the fuck?
我邀请了别人
I invited somebody.
你好
What's good, nigga?
你能来太好了
Glad you could make it.
这发生了什么
What's goin' on?
抱歉 稍等
Be back in a sec, pardon me.
你们有橙子吗？
Y'all got an organ?
柱子和这些东西
Columns and shit.
这里只有你们吗？
It's just y'all here?
对
Yeah.
就是房子的问题
It just makes noises.
好吧
Oh, okay.
你做那把椅子太好了
It's nice to see you in that chair,
我没料到你会选那把
I didn't know you'd pick that one.
谢谢
Thanks a lot, bro.
有点尴尬
Kinda awkward,
这地方很棒啊
but this place is cool.
是啊
Yeah.
吉米对这房子做了很多整修工作
Jimmie's been doing a lot to fix it up.
你们怎么得到这个房子的
How'd y'all get this?
是吉米的
It's Jimmie's.
他爷爷盖的
His grandpa built it.
他是旧金山的第一个黑人
He was the first black man in San Francisco.
他们就是那样叫他的
That's what they call him anyways.
哦
Oh, shit.
- 这就是那座房子? - 嗯
- This that house? - Hmm.
嘿 吉米过去总是在讲这个地方
Hey, Jimmie used to talk about this spot all the time.
在教养院里的黑人
But you know how niggas be in the group home.
人们总是喜欢吹牛
Overexaggerating and shit.
把自己变得厉害之类的
Trying to be all special.
但是你没有撒谎 吉米
You weren't lying about this one, though, huh, Jimmie?
你待过教养院?
You were in a group home?
嗯
Yeah.
有一年吧
For like a year.
是啊
Yep.
你们想去蒸俄罗斯桑拿吗？
You guys wanna go for a schvitz?
什么？
A what?
这也是你爷爷做的吗？
Wait, your grandfather made this too?
不是 那是白人做的
Nah. Nah, these white people did.
啊哈
Uh-huh.
不过 你是怎么知道他是第一个黑人
Well, how you know he was the first one, though?
骗人
Nigga be lyin'.
他从新奥尔良来
Bro, he came over here from New Orleans.
那里全是日本人
There was hella Japanese people, bro.
然后他们就被扔进了集中营
And then they got thrown into little war camps
他从来没有想过要搬进别人的房子
and he wasn't tryin' to move into nobody else's shit,
所以他盖了这座房子
so he built this, bro.
太棒了
This is great.
你还在玩滑板吧？
You still skate, bro?
没有
Nah.
我不玩了
No, I don't skate no more.
你以前可是个菜鸟
Oh, shit, I mean, you used to be hella raw.
是啊
Yeah.
不晓得
I don't know, I'm, uh...
还记得贡纳吗？
Hey, you remember Gunna?
还记得他因为偷糖果女孩的东西被抓吗
Remember when he got caught stealing from the candy lady?
他真是又丑又喜欢大叫
Yeah, he's an ugly-ass crier, really.
天啊
Oh, man.
痛死了
Hurt as fuck!
嘿 记得荷马女士吗？
Hey, remember, uh, Ms. Homer,
管教养院的那位吗？
the one that ran the group home?
- 对 - 她把那货的头发剪了
- Oh yeah! - And she cut that nigga hair,
剪得歪歪扭扭的
had his line crooked!
糟透了
Hella much!
他叫着"那位白人女士不会剪头发"
He goin', "Damn, that white lady couldn't cut no hair!"
那货看起来像是伦巴族的
Had that nigga's shit lookin' like Lombard Street.
伦巴族的
That nigga said Lomb...
都快把我笑尿了
Aw, man, you niggas gonna make me piss on myself.
这大房子上面
Oh, shit, y'all got a bathroom up in here, man?
有浴室吗？
In this big-ass house?
在下面门厅
It's down the hall.
有一个有爪形浴缸的房间
It's the room with the little claw-foot tub.
太棒了 大房子
Aight, this cool as shit, big-ass house.
天啊
Mans...
真希望我也有一个跟你一样的爷爷
I wish I had a grandpa like you.
有这些东西
Need me some shit like this.
这玩意儿爽死了
This shit is enjoyable.
就是这样
Right on, bro.
我为你自豪 你也是 蒙特
I'm proud of you niggas. You too, Mont.
疯子
Crazy-ass.
就这样过日子
Just living the life, man.
你们都成功了
Y'all niggas just really done made it, man.
我得快点去用浴室了
Aw, shit, I"m gonna go use this bathroom real quick.
你个搞笑的混球 吉米
You a funny motherfucker, Jimmie.
"你个搞笑的混球 吉米"
"You a funny motherfucker, Jimmie."
你该...
You should, uh...
你该有个自己的房间
You should have your own room, bro.
没事的 吉姆
That's okay, Jim.
不 没开玩笑
Nah, seriously, man.
我也经常去你那
I been in your space forever.
这里也属于你
This place is yours, too.
哪个房间都行？
Any room?
这个怎么样？
How about this one?
确定要餐厅吗？
Are you sure you want the dining room?
嗯
Yeah.
这里太好了
It's perfect.
选择不错 哥们
Dream big, bro.
是你的了
It's yours.
哇
Wow.
我们得弄清楚是怎么回事
Yeah, we're gonna have to figure something out.
我没那么多时间
I don't have that much time.
情况很复杂
It's a complicated situation.
不 有电
No, the power's been on,
我只是需要我的账单
I just need the bill in my name.
好的
Uh-huh.
好的 什么时候能拿到第一张发票？
Okay, great. Well, when will I get the first invoice?
你不能尽早寄过来吗？
And you can't mail that any sooner?
好的
All right, yeah.
他在说什么付账单
He's talking about paying some bills.
要是他想给小姑娘多点
'Cause I wouldn't say no
我也不会拒绝的
if he offered to chip in a little more.
他已经付了一半了 爷爷
He already pays half, Grandpa.
他在这里待了一段时间了
Well, he's been here for a while, you know?
他也不是我们的家人
And he is not exactly family.
他很清楚
I think he knows that.
希望如此
Let's hope so.
那么吵是怎么回事
What's all this noise up in here?
我在打包一些东西
I'm just packing some stuff.
有一个项目
It's for a project.
什么时候开始的
Since when?
我们都还没有谈一下角色
I mean, we haven't even talked about the characters yet.
我很喜欢那个的
You know how much I like that.
嗯 我还在写
Yeah, well... I'm still working on it.
还没有具体的情节
Don't quite have a plot yet.
我们可以头脑风暴一下
Well, we can brainstorm a little bit.
我觉得我们最擅长
You know, that's where I think we the best at.
头脑风暴了
When we brainstorming.
这次我得自己
I think I gotta brainstorm this one
想了
by myself right now.
但是很快我就会和你谈谈的
But I'd love to talk about it soon.
你准备好了吗？
You 'bout ready, bro?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
嗯...
Well, um...
不管怎样
Whatever it is, uh...
我都为你自豪
I'm proud of you.
喔 看他
Wow, look at him.
那是什么鞋？
What type of shoes are those?
要搞摇滚吗？
Yeah, you should start rocking like that, bra-bra.
吉米 你那帽子是怎么回事？
What the fuck is up with your hat, Jimmie?
看起来像个人形烟卷 我受不了了
You look like a human cigarette, I can't handle it.
吉米 那是个保龄球吗？
Jimmie, is that a bowling ball?
那是黑人爱丽丝梦游仙境吗？
It's the black Alice and Wonderland.
蒙蒂 我听见了
Hey, Monty, bro, I heard you be whippin' out
你用小鸡鸡抽打女孩
that little weenie on all the girls.
那头发 你像辛普森
Bro, with that hair, you look like a Simpson.
闭嘴吧 你个只有一条衬衫的货
Nigga, shut up, bro, your one-shirt-havin' ass.
吉米 你他妈的每天都穿一样的衬衫
Jimmie, you wear the same shirt every motherfuckin' day.
你是魔鬼吧 吉米
You look like a fiend, Jimmie, come on!
和你爸一样
Hey, just like your daddy!
我记得
I remember!
你那个瘾君子老爹
Your crackhead-ass daddy.
还有哑巴恶魔老妈
And your dumb-fiend-ass mom.
一家子恶魔 狗比
Family of fiends, dog.
我还记得那天卖给他过一块石头
I done sold him a rock back in the day.
你那里面都有啥？
Hey, what you got up in there?
给你那大房子装扮的
Some lace curtains for that whole
蕾丝窗帘吗
beautifyin'-ass house
那个你们一直在打扮的玩意儿
that y'all been makin' up and shit?
科菲 还有啥
Okay, Kofi! Okay, what else?
听着 那天那俩黑鬼
Hey, look! These niggas the other day,
- 他们那天 - 怎么了
- they pulled up the other day. - Uh-huh.
那房子里全是一些
Niggas had all types of feminine shit
女人用的玩意儿
goin' on in that house, bro.
吉米 俩大老爷们在那里干啥呢？
Jimmie, what two men do that?
你住进了那个大房子
Just 'cause you in that big ass house,
并不代表你比我们强 吉米
you not better than us, Jimmie.
- 永远都是 - 你不比我们强
- Never. - You're not better than us.
嘿 那是什么 蕾丝窗帘吗？
Hey, what is those, lace curtains
用这玩意儿打扮房子吗？
you gonna beautify the house with?
得了吧 娘炮
Come on, man, soft-ass nigga.
吉米 你给我记住了 我知道你是谁
I know who you is, Jimmie, remember!
知道你们要做什么吗？
Hey, you know what y'all need to do?
你们得消失
Y'all need to disappear
就像他妈的魔法秀一样
like a motherfuckin' magic trick, nigga!
傻逼帽子见鬼去吧 赶紧滚
Rabbit out the hat, get the fuck out here.
快滚
Fuck outta here!
吉米 吉米 回家吧
Jimmie! Jimmie! Go home!
你真的在画他们吗？
You're really drawing them?
他们嘴臭的要死
They just talk shit.
我刚见到你的时候 你也是这样
Well, you talked shit when I met you.
是吗？
I did?
是的
You did.
不过 没事
It's fine, though.
为什么和我一起玩
Why'd you hang out with me, then?
你在乎很多事情 我喜欢你
You care about things. I liked you.
你真的他妈的一点都不在乎别人说什么吗？
You really don't give a fuck what anybody says?
我不该去感谢他们
I shouldn't get to appreciate them
因为他们对我很刻薄？
'cause they're mean to me?
太傻了
That's silly.
哦
Oh.
呼
Phew.
你在这干嘛？
What are you doing here?
你一直都在这干嘛？
What are you ever doing here?
呃...
Uh...
你没搬出去吗？
Didn't you move out, though?
搬了
Yeah.
他们把锁换了
They changed the fuckin' locks on me.
抱歉 太糟糕了
I'm sorry, that sucks.
你要干什么啊？
What do you want, man?
你要在这待多久？
How long you gonna be here?
还不知道
I don't know yet.
我只是尽力地...
I'm just tryin' to...
放手
Let go.
好吧
Okay, well...
那我们明天再来
I guess we'll just come back tomorrow then.
好极了
Great.
好
That's nice.
走吧 吉姆 去我家
Come on, Jim, we'll go to my house.
你仍然待在这座疯狂的城市里
In this crazy fuckin' city, you're still here.
这些倒霉催的孩子扔的到处都是泡泡糖
Man, those damn kids dropping bubble gum all over the place,
你座位上都是
it'll get all over your seat, man.
知道我在说什么了吧
You know what I'm sayin'?
她会在那过夜吗?
Think she'll stay there all night?
走着瞧吧 我们会回来的
Watch, we'll come back
她说不定在给窗沿涂漆
and she'll be painting the windowsill.
好的 我会去的
Yes, baby. Yes, I will be there.
我已经戒了三年了
I've been clean for three years,
我知道在哪开会
I know where those meetings are.
好的 知道了
All right, you got it.
我会提前15分钟到
I'll be there 15 minutes early.
好的 我告诉...
Yes. Yes, I told...
吉宝？
Jayboe?
吉宝
Jayboe.
呃
Uh...
嗨 妈妈
Hi, Mom.
嗨
Hi.
喔 妈妈
Wow, Mom.
见到你真高兴
Good to see you.
- 嗨 - 喔
- Hi. - Wow.
- 嗯 对 对不起 - 没关系的
- Um, yeah. Uh, I'm sorry. - That's all right.
我以为你和罗恩在洛杉矶
I thought you and Ron were in LA.
不 我们回这已经有三个月了
Oh, no, we been back for three months now.
嗯...
Uh...
这是我朋友 蒙特
This is my friend, Mont.
你好 我是吉米的妈妈
Oh, hi, 'scuse me, I'm Jimmie's mom,
很高兴见到你
nice to meet you.
Pleasure to meet you.
- 你也是 - 嗯...
- You too, sir. - Yeah, well...
我们住在那座房子里
We been staying at the house.
要是 你...
If, uh, you know...
你可以顺便过来
You should stop by.
过来看看
You know, come check it out.
哦 好的好的
Oh, that's nice. Yeah.
那座房子 我爸爸的老房子
The house, my dad's old house.
哦 你家族的房子
Oh, your family house,
- 在金门? - 对
- on Golden Gate? - Yeah.
好的 我有你的电话 会打给你的
Okay. Well, I got your number, I'll call you.
尽量明天就过去
Try to come over there tomorrow.
我没有电话
Oh, I don't have a phone.
那我直接过去就行了
Well, I just have to come over there, then.
最好什么时候过去?我明天就过去
What's the best time to come? I'll be over there tomorrow.
什么时候都行
Well, yeah, whenever.
来...行
Come... Yeah.
明天 行
Tomorrow, yeah, fuck it.
好的
Okay.
- 好的 明天过去 - 好的
- Cool, I'll be there tomorrow. - Okay.
好
Yeah.
嗯...
Well...
我要在这站下了
Our stop's coming up, but...
嗯...见到你真的很开心 妈
Uh... It was really nice to see you, Mom.
Well, it was good to see you too, son, okay?
好的
Yeah.
- 好的 - 好的
- All right. - All right.
- 好的 再见 - 好的
- All right, bye now. - Okay.
天哪 你现在比我高了
Okay. Oh, my God, you taller than me now.
- 是的 呃...- 再见了 孩子
- Yeah, uh... - Okay, bye, son.
嗯 再见
Yeah, bye. Uh...
为什么?为什么?
Why? Why?
怎么了？
What happened?
为什么？
Why?
什么鬼？
What the fuck?
发生什么了？
What happened?
- 他妈的发生了什么? - 他中枪了
- What the fuck happened? - He got shot.
他们向他开枪了
They shot him.
谁? 谁开枪了？
Who? Who shot him?
谁？
Who?
海湾那边的黑鬼
Bay niggas.
为了什么？
For what?
他对他们说了脏话
He was talking shit to the wrong niggas.
想吓唬吓唬他们
Tried to bluff some niggas out.
吓唬吓唬？
Tried to bluff them out?
哪来的这么多问题？
Man, what's with all the questions, bro?
我不明白
I just don't get it.
我只看到你们
I just fuckin' seen y'all.
怎么了？
And nigga?
我他妈的不明白
And I don't fucking get it!
呃 天
Tsk. Man.
滚吧 哥们
Get the fuck up outta here, bro.
我滚出去？
Me get the fuck outta here?
- 就是你 - 是你的错
- Yes, nigga, go! - It's your fucking fault!
他也是我的朋友
That's my fuckin' friend, too!
- 好吧 - 干他
- All right, nigga. - Get on this nigga!
好的
All right.
干他
Push up on this nigga, bro.
你他么的听得下去？
You finna let him say that?
可怜的孩子和他的朋友
That poor boy and his friends.
对不起 吉米
I'm sorry, Jimmie.
我不希望让你感觉在这里不受欢迎
I hope I never made you feel like you weren't welcome here.
没有...我没感觉到那样
No, I... I never felt like that.
因为你在哪里我一点都不在乎
'Cause I don't care where you been.
你没必要告诉我
You don't have to tell me.
只是 你俩
It's just, you two
老是黏在一起
stick together.
我在写一出关于他的戏
You know, I was writing a play about him.
你没必要停
You don't have to stop now.
"吉米 你个搞笑的混球"
"You a funny motherfucker, Jimmie."
我知道听起来很诡异 但是...
I know it sounds weird, but...
感觉如果不是房子的事
I kinda feel like that could've been me.
那可能就是我了
If not for the house.
我想回家
Man, I wanna go home.
肮脏的 海水
Filthy, fishy salt water.
臭气熏天已经
Water been funkier than the Devil's mouth
有50年了
for 50 years.
现在他们想要清理了
Now they wanna clean it up.
他们都计划好了
They've got plans for us.
我们被迫忍受地狱般的环境
We was made to be put through Hell.
锤炼...我们被迫忍受地狱般的环境
Purified... We was made to be put through Hell.
得到锤炼
Be purified.
该死
Fuck!
哦 老天
Oh, God.
该死
Fuck!
她是怎么把我们的东西都扔出来的？
How did she toss all of our shit?
不是她
I don't think it was her.
该死的骗子
Fuckin' traitor.
好的
Okay.
你能呆在这看一下东西吗？
Can you stay here and watch the shit?
可以 你去哪？
Yeah, where you going?
- 你去哪？- 我会回来的
- Where you going? - I'll be back.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
吉米
Jimmie!
抱歉 有什么可以为你效劳的？
Sorry, uh, how can I help you today?
呃...
Uh...
- 我要买座房子 -一座房子
- I want to buy a house. - A house?
挺好的
That's exciting.
你有中介吗？
Uh, are you working with an agent?
没有 有必要吗？
No. Do I need to?
没有
No.
没有必要 嗯...
Not necessarily. Um...
你可以接受的价格大概是多少呢？
Do you have a price range in mind?
我已经有看中的房子了
I have a house in mind.
哦
Oh.
嗯...
Um...
那应该已经在市场上待售了吧
It's on the market, I assume?
他们要多少钱？
How much are they asking?
至少4百万美金
At least $4 million.
嗯...你出什么价呢？
Uh... And how much are you willing to put down?
一般该出什么价？
How much is usual?
一般 安全价大概至少降百分之二十
Well, typically, we'd be looking to secure at least 20%.
我没有那么多钱
I wouldn't have that.
可以理解
That's understandable.
买这块地的话
It's going to be hard to land a place like that.
如果是我的话...
But suppose I ask instead, uh...
不 不 听着
No, no, look.
我知道的
I get it.
我太年轻了
I'm young.
我是黑人
Uh, I'm black.
我不富有
I'm not rich.
我都知道的
I came here knowing all that.
但是让我们都现实点 你也有限额要达成
But let's be real, you also got a quota to meet.
我也不会说你
Now I'm not calling you
- 欺负人 - 先生
- a predator... - Sir.
你也只是在挣钱而已
But you're trying to make your money.
- 就让我帮你吧 - 先生
- So let me help you do that. - Sir.
这样是行不通的
That's not the way this works.
你给我什么价我都接受
You can give me whatever deal you gotta give me. I don't care what it is.
因为不像其他人那么随便
'Cause unlike all the other people that default,
这是我一直想住的房子
this is the only house I'll ever want.
每月的账单我都会付
So I'll never miss a monthly bill, ever.
你可以给我开最高利息的价 好吗？
You can give me your highest interest rate.
我理解
I completely understand how you feel, sir.
你可以给我开最高利息的价 好吗？
You can give me your highest interest rate, okay?
- 随便搞我 - 不 我完全...
- Fuck... Fuck me. - No, I completely...
都不用感到内疚
You don't even have to feel bad.
好吗？我会毫厘不差的付给你
Okay? I will pay back every single cent.
抱歉 先生
I'm sorry, sir.
我会毫厘不差的付给你
I will pay back every single cent.
好的 好的 你赢了
Okay, okay, you win!
好了 是你的了
Okay, yep, it's yours.
你个混蛋 说的太有吸引力了
You charming bastard, okay.
一会儿再跟你聊 再见
Talk to you soon, buh-bye.
最近怎么样啊 哥们
How's it going, man?
还好
Fine, sir.
我看到我们聊过的那座房子正在待售
I noticed the house we discussed is now for sale.
在你们的相关文献中 有一些警告
There are some alarming elements in your literature
你应该知道
I thought you would like to know.
房产局也是
And certainly the Bureau of Real Estate would.
好的
Uh-huh.
这里声称
This claims
那里的产权属于金门景观
the property has a view of the Golden Gate.
而...
Which...
那是假的
I don't think is true.
呃
Well,
不是 不是真的
it isn't. It isn't true.
还声称原有的
It also claims to have all the original
"设备 地板 水龙头"
"fixtures, floors, and faucets."
不对
Isn't true.
你是想说
And are you planning on disclosing
没有化粪池吗？
that there's no septic tank?
那意味着 任一天
Which means, any day now,
那个花园都有可能
the garden could be flooded
被屎淹没
with shit.
发生了什么？
Where's this going, man?
嗯...
Well...
你们的售卖似乎都是
All this together seems like false advertisement.
基于虚假的宣传
Which is grounds for void a sale.
有可能被吊销执照
Potential revoke of license.
我就知道是你们
I thought it might've been you guys.
你出什么价
What's your deal, man?
没有出价
Don't have a deal.
嗯...听着
Hmm. Look...
这层楼的任何一个人
Somebody on this floor
都有可能去卖那座房子 如果不是我的话
would've gotten that house if it wasn't me.
至少你们认识我 对吗？
At least I'm from here, right?
我把你们的东西放在街边
I put your stuff on the street
- 是做了个好事 - 好的
- as a favor. - Okay.
我本可以直接让卡车拉走
I could've had it trucked away,
但是我给你们留下来了
but I left it out for you.
你听着 混蛋
Look, dick wad.
我没开玩笑 我会去举报你的
I'm not fucking around, I will report you.
因为什么？
For what?
桥景的一部分?设备？
Listing a view of the bridge? And fixtures?
所有人都那样做的
Everybody does that.
我只是粘贴复制的
I literally copy-pasted that shit.
你们对那房子的历史撒谎了
Well, you're lying about the history of the house.
那我没有撒谎
I'm not lying about that.
你在撒谎 你说的时间
Yes, you are! You say it was built
比真正建造的时间早了一百年
one hundred years earlier than it actually was.
Look, I'm not making this up.
你就在撒谎
Yes, you are!
詹姆斯·菲尔斯在1946年盖的
James Fails built this house in 1946.
- 詹姆斯? -菲尔斯
- James? - Fails!
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
听着
Look, man.
信托契约 1857年
Deed of Trust, 1857.
建造师吉尔·胡里什么的
Architect Gil-hoo-ley, some shit.
你说的菲尔斯在90年左右抵押了
Your guy Fails lost it in the '90s.
看 在这
See, right there.
听着
Look, man.
要是你还需要一周时间找找其他地方的话 就拿着
If you need a week to find somewhere else, then take it.
但是...
But...
别再说我是什么非法占地的了
Don't go pulling some squatters rights shit on me, man.
我有你的邮件地址
I got your mail.
我知道你的名字
I know your name.
我不想叫警察
I don't want to call the cops.
你去哪了？
I don't want to do that to you.
不重要了
Where'd you go?
我把东西都搬进去了
Doesn't matter, bro.
只剩下沙发
I got everything inside.
那玩意儿差点砸到我
Except the couch.
吉姆...
That shit almost fell on me.
我
Jim...
跟房产经纪人谈了谈
I spoke to the realtor.
好吧 去他的
Yeah, fuck that guy.
他要把我们赶出去
He's gonna throw us out.
还要叫警察
And eventually call the cops.
我不晓得我们还能这样多久
I don't know how much longer we can keep doing this.
要是你坚持不下去了我能理解
I understand if you can't.
确实
I do.
但是我不会离开
But I'm not leaving.
- 吉姆 他说你爷... - 我能去哪？
- Jim, he said your grand... - Where am I gonna go?
我爸在自律组织里
My dad's in the SRO.
姑姑在那个破地方
My aunt's out in bum fuck.
我妈...
My mom...
我甚至都不知道我妈在那
Bro, I don't even know where my mom is.
我不会走的
I'm not leaving, bro.
我是最后一个了
I'm the last one left.
我们还有我的房子
We have my house.
我不能回那里
I can't go back there, bro.
蒙特
Mont,
这座房子...
this house...
这是我想待的地方
This is what I do.
这是我们想待的地方 蒙特
Hey, it's what we do, Mont.
这是我们的
This is our shit.
我们还不能放弃
We can't give up now.
得继续抗争
We gotta fight.
对吗？
Right?
对
Yeah.
我会在你身边的
I'm with you, bro.
你总是在我身边
You always been with me.
你在写作吗？
Oh, shit, you're writing?
是
Yeah. Uh...
我有突破了
I think I cracked a play.
我想下周就开演
I'd like to put it on next week,
如果可以的话？
if that's all right?
当然了 去吧 哥们
Hell, yeah, get it, bro!
♪♪ 嘿
♪♪ Hey
♪♪ 嘿 耶
♪♪ Hey, yeah
♪♪ 要是你去洛杉矶的话
♪♪ If you're going to San Francisco
♪♪ 一定要在头上
♪♪ Be sure to wear
♪♪ 戴着花
♪♪ Flowers in your hair
♪♪ 要是你来到
♪♪ If you come
♪♪ 旧金山的话
♪♪ To San Francisco
♪♪ 你会遇到
♪♪ You're gonna meet
♪♪ 一些谦虚的人
♪♪ Some gentle people there
♪♪ 谦虚的人
♪♪ Gentle people
♪♪ Gentle people there
♪♪ 谦虚的人
♪♪ Gentle people
♪♪ 来到
♪♪ Will be a love-in there
♪♪ 洛杉矶的人们
♪♪ For those who come
♪♪ 你们会受到欢迎
♪♪ To San Francisco
♪♪ 夏日时光
♪♪ Summertime
♪♪ 你们会受到欢迎
♪♪ Will be a love-in there
♪♪ 在旧金山
♪♪ In the streets
♪♪ 街头
♪♪ Of San Francisco
好啊
Yeah.
怎么写的这么快
How'd you write all this that fast?
还有更多
There's more.
但是我更希望你单独看完
But I'd rather you saw the rest in person.
♪♪ 要是你来到旧金山
♪♪ If you come to San Francisco
♪♪ 夏日时光
♪♪ Summertime
♪♪ 将会
♪♪ Will be
♪♪ 受到欢迎 ♪♪
♪♪ A love-in there ♪♪
- 不错 - 谢谢 先生
- That was good. - Thank you, sir.
你还会什么？
What else you got?
♪♪ 我为其欢呼 ♪♪
♪♪ I got five on it ♪♪
哦 耶
Oh, yeah.
♪♪ 拿上你的... ♪♪
♪♪ Grab your four... ♪♪
- 哦 抱歉 - 不 继续
- Oh, I'm sorry. - No, keep going!
蒙特?
Mont?
真他么的早
Hella fuckin' early.
好吧
Here we go.
你为什么穿得像个白人男孩？
Why are you dressed like a white boy?
哦...
Oh...
是为了那个小节目 对吧？
It's for your little show, huh?
天
Man.
你拿我爸的椅子干啥?蒙特戈里
You mess up my daddy's chair, Montgomery?
哈？
Huh?
不
No.
不是 先生 我们...只是...
No, sir, we... We were just...
结结巴巴的怎么了?
What you stuttering for?
现在就怯场了吗？
You got stage fright already? Huh?
不是
No.
我不在乎那椅子 孩子
I don't care about the chair, son.
但是要轻点
But be easy with it.
谢谢
Thank you.
继续
Carry on.
呼
Phew.
我弹这个的时候我爸真是恨死了
My daddy hated when I played that shit.
好 快进来 别害羞
Yeah, come on in, don't be shy.
他爷爷做的
His grandpa built it.
一个黑人搞得还不错 是吧？
Not bad for a black man, huh?
哦 不
Oh, no.
很好
Very good.
这一定很有趣
So, this is gonna be interesting.
不错
This is nice.
- 观众也很多啊 - 是啊
- Nice crowd, too. - Yeah.
你靠糖果赚了很多钱吗？
You make a lot of money on candy?
买糖果？
Sell candy?
- 过去卖过几年 - 是吗？
- I used to, for years. - Oh, yeah?
大多数搬进这个
Most of these new white people
黑人聚集区的白人
that's moving in these black neighborhoods,
都不知道他们站在厨房的位置
they don't even know they standing in the kitchen
- 就是一兄弟中枪的地方 - 嗯
- where a dude got shot at. - Mmm.
我都不知道他在搞戏剧这些东西
I didn't know he was doing a play and shit.
他邀请了我们
He just invited us,
也不知道他要搞什么古怪的东西
I don't know what weird shit they got goin' on,
确实挺怪异的
but it's pretty weird.
我为什么要打你？
What I'mma hit you for?
你是我的兄弟
You my folks.
好的
All right.
但是我身边不准有胆小鬼
But I can't have soft niggas hanging around me.
打我
Hit me.
不
Nah!
不 为什么?
Nah! For what, nigga?
打我
Hit me.
雄起 雄起
Man up, nigga. Man up!
不
No, bro!
不 不 不
No! No, bro, no!
你个胆小鬼
Oh, you soft.
You soft, nigga.
他们给你送葬的时候会叫你贱货
They gonna call you a bitch at your funeral.
我不是贱货
I ain't no bitch!
我不是贱货 我是个男人
I ain't no bitch! I'm a man!
那打我啊
Then hit me.
打我 打我
Hit me, bro. Hit me.
打我
Hit me, nigga.
好的
All right!
Yeah!
这
Here, nigga.
老子不在乎
I don't give a fuck.
来看我
Come see me, nigga.
谁躲在外面？
Who out there hiding?
雄起
Man up!
Man up, nigga!
-雄起 - 嘿
- Man up! - Hey!
不用打字
No words.
No words!
发送拥抱表情就行了
Please send e-hugs.
黑泽·格林
Hazel Greene.
一百三十五个赞
One hundred and thirty-five likes.
该死
Damn!
总有一天把你烧死
Just smoked with you the other day!
疯了
Crazy!
约翰·毕肖普
John Bishop.
两百六十个赞
Two hundred and sixty likes.
十个分享
Ten shares.
这些人里
Are these the people
有人认识科菲的吗？
who knew Kofi?
因为迟到被该死的老板骂了
Got yelled at by my bitch boss for being late!
抱歉
Sorry!
别找借口
There's no timer for grief.
利亚田中 320个赞
Leah Tanaka, 320 likes.
天啊
Man!
不敢相信我失去了我的兄弟
Man! Can't believe we lost my bro!
但是你别想让我感到悲伤 小科
But you wouldn't want me to be sad, Ko,
我把我的痛苦都写进了音乐
so I put my pain into my music!
保证你喜欢这次的动态
Make sure you like the post.
罗 罗 罗德尼·塔克
Ro-Ro-Ro-Rodney Tuck.
塔克先生
Mr. Tuck
十年前
moved to Florida
搬到了佛罗里达
ten years ago!
这些人里
Are these the people
有认识科菲的吗？
who knew Kofi?
科菲有自己的人生
Kofi had dimensions.
不只是...
More than a...
一个可以转发的动态 或者一出戏就可以演完的
A post could reflect or a play could capture.
所以我请求你们
So I summon you.
为他的生命欢呼
Celebrate the life he lived.
不是用最大的嗓子
Not through those who speak the loudest.
而是用他留给我们的回忆
But through the memories he left us all.
女士
Ma'am!
- 我？- 是的 你将怎么...
- Me? - Mmm. How will you...
你将怎么怀念科菲？
How will you remember Kofi?
嗯...
Um...
我侄女刚搬到这里的时候
He, you know, he used to come and walk my niece
他会送她去学校
home from school when she first moved up here.
他很有礼貌 有点古板
He was a little gentleman, or whatnot,
很贴心 嗯...
you know, sweet, um...
只是伤心
It's just sad.
嗯
Mmm.
- 在华纳青年联盟的时候我教过科菲 - 好的
- I coached Kofi in Pop Warner. - Mmm-hmm.
他在后台帮我整理东西器具
He stayed behind and helped me pack up.
天天如此
Every day.
好的
Yeah.
你呢?年轻人
And how 'bout you, young man?
该死的
Shit, man.
我不知道
I don't know.
我是不是逼他太紧了？
Did I push him too hard?
科菲是我兄弟
Kofi was my nigga, man.
我是不是逼他太紧了？
Did I push him too hard?
好的 你呢？
Mmm. How 'bout you?
嗯...
Well...
我对科菲最后的记忆是
My last memory of Kofi
他在对我说脏话
was him talking shit to me.
他说了一些最糟糕的混蛋
He said some of the most fucked-up shit
都不会对我说的话
anybody's ever said to me.
但是在教养院的时候
But Kofi also got jumped
他也会为我
for defending me against the older kids
去对抗那些年长的孩子
in the group home.
他不喜欢打架
He didn't like to fight,
但是那个时候他却为我挺身而出
but he fought for me then.
不能片面的判断一个人
People aren't one thing.
那个
That.
All...
All of it.
What would have happened
if Kofi could've
showed himself?
All forms of himself.
The world
put him in a box!
And he never
pushed beyond it.
Let us.
Let us break the boxes!
Let us give each other the courage!
To... To see!
Beyond the stories we are born into!
Let us all
really look
at Jimmie Fails IV.
Self-taught historian.
Carpenter.
Gentle, loving man.
A true survivor. Jimmie!
How many places have you lived?
And if they kicked you out tomorrow,
you would still be all those things!
You exist beyond the...
These walls, you extend beyond your...
Your... Your forefathers!
You are more than this house!
Jimmie, you are not these... These walls!
You're not these floors, you're not this ceiling!
- It's time you know! - Bro, what are you doing?
- What are you doing? - It is time!
- It is time you know! - I don't need to know,
I don't need to know. Let's stop. Let's stop.
- Jimmie... You don't! - Enough, stop!
- Please, stop. Mont! - Jimmie!
Your grandpa didn't build this house!
Enough!
He didn't build it, Jimmie!
他盖了
Yes, he did.
- 他盖的这座房子 - 他没有 我看见了
- He built this house! - He didn't, I saw it, man,
我看见了契据
I saw the deed.
我看到了
I saw it.
不晓得那是什么鬼
I don't know what the hell that thing was.
然后他来了个左勾拳
Then he shoots a left. Psh!
哈
Ha!
让他们走吧
Man, let 'em leave.
反正他们没有资格在这
They don't deserve to be in here anyway.
我们也是
Neither do we.
你真的要让其他人
You gonna really listen to what
告诉你什么是真的吗？
another-ass nigga tell you what's true?
好了 吉宝 振作起来
Come on, Jayboe, get your spine up, son.
- 骄傲起来 - 我正在这样做
- Have some pride, man. - I've been doin'.
但是你说
But you say it.
说什么？
Say what?
真相
The truth.
什么？
What?
爷爷没有盖那座房子
That grandpa didn't build this house.
那都是放屁
Tsk. Man, get outta here with that bullshit.
振作起来 吉宝
Come on, Jayboe.
说吧
Just say it.
我不能说
Can't tell you shit.
我出去了
I'm outta here, man.
你继续坐在那吧
You sit in that bullshit if you want.
吉宝
Jayboe.
一直以来我都在跟别人说他盖的
I been telling people he built it for so long.
都快忘记那不是真的了
Almost forgot it wasn't true.
这里是我们的
This was ours.
不在是了
And then it wasn't.
你要是还觉得这是我们的
So you just tell yourself what you need
就继续自己骗自己吧
to make you feel like it still is.
该死
Shit.
我也这样做了
I did it, too.
让你感觉
It makes you feel
与众不同
special.
但是现在
But you got a chance to get out
你有机会摆脱这些了
from underneath all of that now.
我不想
I don't want to.
我只是想要它
I just want it.
这真的就是你想要的吗？
Is that what you really want?
花费你后半生的时间为此工作
To spend the rest of your life working for this?
抗争？
Fighting for this?
我相信
I believe that
你能把这里变成你的
you could make this place yours.
真的
I really do.
但是你放下的话
But if you leave
也没有损失什么
it's not your loss.
这是旧金山的
It's San Francisco's.
去他的旧金山
Fuck San Francisco.
- 这城市完了 - 彻底的
- This city blows. - Big time.
我的意思是我不会
I mean, whatever, I'm not above
住在以前是个破破烂烂的房子里的
living in a former crack house, you know?
我来这是为了贾妮斯和在飞机上工作
But, I came here for Janis and the Airplane,
不是为了该死的首付
not to work at a fucking startup.
兄弟 我都说了几个月了
Dude, I've been saying for months,
我们搬到洛杉矶东部吧
let's just move to East LA.
这座城完蛋了
This city's dead.
不
Nah.
真的 这座该死的城市
Seriously, fuck this city.
真的吗？
'Scuse me?
你没必要仇恨旧金山啊
You don't get to hate San Francisco.
抱歉 什么？
I'm sorry, what?
好了 哥们 我是说...
Yeah, dude, I mean...
抱歉 我想恨什么就恨什么
Sorry, but I'll hate what I want.
你热爱这座城吗？
Do you love it?
这个...我住在这里
It's... I mean yeah, I'm here.
但是我热爱这里吗？
But do I have to love it?
你不会讨厌它 除非你喜欢它
You don't get to hate it unless you love it.
典型的公交车无聊废话
Classic Muni shit.
该谁付钱了 快点 哥们
Who call the money man, come on now, hurry up.
集中精神
Pay attention!
伟人亚历山大是个黑人
Alexander the Great was a black man.
该死的学校不会教你这些
They don't teach you that in the devil school system.
我再也受不了这玩意儿了
I can't take another day of this bullshit.
吉姆
Oh, Jim.
抱歉我之前那样
I'm sorry I did that.
那就是个傻逼戏
It was a stupid play.
不
Nah.
抱歉我没跟你说实话
I'm sorry I didn't tell you the truth.
我也想那是真的
I just wanted it to be true.
感觉很好 不是吗？
It felt so good, you know?
还好
It's okay.
嘿 吉米
Hey, Jimmie.
你饿了吗？
Are you hungry?
饿死了
Fucking starving.
他在放弃
He's giving up.
我再也受不了了
I can't take no more.
他在崩溃
He's breaking down.
哦 哇
Oh, wow.
他真的在拆公寓
He's really tearing this apartment apart.
看起来挺刺激的
This looks exciting though, you know?
- 是 是 - 是吗?真的吗?
- Yeah. Yeah, it is. - Yeah? Oh, yeah?
- 我感觉到了 - 哦
- Oh! I got it now. - Oh!
他看起来像是欲火焚身了
He seems like he's horny or something.
他又在撞门
He's banging on the door again.
我会的
I will.
我今天就离开旧金山
I'm leaving San Francisco today,
但是一周之内我会离开
but I'll be back in about a week,
我会替你照顾好的
I'll take care of it for you then.
我见过他更糟的时候
Well, I've seen him worse.
祝你玩的开心 伯特
Well have a nice time, Bert.
- 好的 谢谢 - 不如你...
- Yeah, thanks. - Why don't you...